It's usually best to find missing data first if you can.
من الأفضل عادةً أن تجد البيانات المفقودة إذا كان ذلك في الإمكان.
In other words, completeness issues,
بمعنى آخر، مشاكل الاكتمال،
which is a part of data quality.
التي هي جزء من جودة البيانات.
Sometimes you can't though, and that's fine.
وأحيانًا لا يمكنك استكمالها، لابأس بذلك.
But if you can find that missing data,
لكن إذا كان يمكنك إيجاد البيانات المفقودة،
concatenate, join, impute, whatever.
تسلسل أو ضم أو إرفاق أو أي شيء.
Get it all intact there so the subsequent cleaning operations you
احصل عليها كلها بدون تغيير فلن تضطر لإعادة
perform on those columns or rows won't have to be redone i.e.
عمليات التنظيف اللاحقة التي تجريها على هذه الأعمدة أو الصفوف، على سبيل المثال،
not filling in the missing data,
عدم ملء البيانات المفقودة،
then cleaning some rows and columns with missing data,
ثم تنظيف بعض الصفوف التي بها بيانات مفقودة،
then joining that missing data in later and having to redo those cleaning operations.
ثم ضم البيانات المفقودة لاحقًا ثم تضطر لإعادة عمليات التنظيف هذه.
So for our clinical trial dataset here,
أما بالنسبة لمجموعة بيانات التجربة الإكلينيكية هنا،
we identified three completeness issues.
فقد حددنا ثلاث مشاكل اكتمال.
Two in the treatments table,
اثنان في جدول العلاج،
the missing HbA1c changes,
تغييرات HbA1c المفقودة،
and the missing records having 280 instead of 350,
والسجلات المفقودة بها 280 بدلاً من 350،
displayed here in the visual assessment.
معروضة هنا في التقييم البصري.
Then one missing data issue in the patients table,
ثم مشكلة بيانات مفقودة في جدول المرضى،
the missing demographic information all displayed here
والمعلومات السكانية المفقودة المعروضة كلها هنا
through the.isnull method on the patient's address column.
من خلال طريقة .isnull في عمود عنوان المريض.
Address, city, state, zip code, country, and contact.
العنوان، المدينة، الولاية، الرمز البريدي، البلد، بيانات الاتصال.
Contact being phone number and email address.
لأن بيانات الاتصال هي رقم التليفون والبريد الالكتروني.
So we can't address this third issue,
لذا لا يمكننا اعتبار هذه المشكلة الثالثة،
the missing demographic information.
هي المعلومات السكانية المفقودة.
Sometimes you just can't, you're stuck.
بعض الأحيان لا يمكنك ذلك، أنت عالق.
We really have no way of getting this information from these people.
ليس لدينا حقًا طريقة للحصول على هذه المعلومات من هؤلاء الأشخاص.
Because we don't know where they live,
لأننا لا نعرف أين يعيشون،
their phone number, or their e-mail address.
أو رقم التليفون، أو البريد الإلكتروني.
We can't contact them.
لا يمكننا الاتصال بهم.
We could skim the phone book or the internet for their contact information,
يمكننا تصفح دليل التليفون أو الانترنت للبحث عن بيانات الاتصال الخاصة بهم،
but it's probably most efficient to hold off until they come back
لكن الأكثر فعالية أن ننظر حتى يعودون
into our office or the hospital for example.
إلى مكتبنا أو المستشفى على سبيل المثال.
We can clean the other two issues though,
مع ذلك يمكننا تنظيف المشكلتين الآخرتين،
the two in the treatments table.
في جدول العلاج.
Missing HbA1c changes and the missing records,
تغييرات HbA1c المفقودة والسجلات المفقودة،
280 instead of 350. Let's get to those now.
280 بدلاً من 350. لنتحدث عنهم الآن.